<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: octopress | A coder in the attic]]></title>
  <link href="http://huuhoa.blackci.com/blog/categories/octopress/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://huuhoa.blackci.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-07T22:15:47+07:00</updated>
  <id>http://huuhoa.blackci.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Huu Hoa NGUYEN]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[huuhoa@blackci.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thinking of solutions for remote blogging with Octopress]]></title>
    <link href="http://huuhoa.blackci.com/blog/2014/01/31/thinking-of-solutions-for-remote-blogging-with-octopress/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-31T23:51:51+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://huuhoa.blackci.com/blog/2014/01/31/thinking-of-solutions-for-remote-blogging-with-octopress</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After done setting up blogging solution with Octopress, which is this blog is now powered by, I&rsquo;m thinking of finding a solution to write blog post from iPhone. The first site came up from Google results is <a href="http://www.candlerblog.com/2012/04/01/remote-octopress-workflow">this one</a>. The solution seems very neat, it involves setting up a shared folder on Dropbox and a SSH server to run the Octopress flows. Setup a shared folder in Dropbox for holding git repository is easy part. The harder part is getting a always-on SSH server.</p>

<p>Currently I think of three solutions:</p>

<ol>
<li>Make use of existing SmartTV box which is now running Android 4.2 to be a SSH server</li>
<li>Purchase a minimal VPS instance.</li>
<li>Purchase a Raspberry Pi and make it a SSH server</li>
</ol>


<p>First solution is free because I already have one SmartTV box. However making Android box running RVM seems to be a difficult task. Further search, there is an attempt to <a href="http://forum.xda-developers.com/showthread.php?t=1585009">run a Linux distro on Android</a>. It looks promising and worth a try.</p>

<p>Second solution will cost at least 5$/month for a VPS instance. Which is not a good way to go at the moment.</p>

<p>Third solution will cost about 40$ and I&rsquo;ll got a Raspberry Pi for something else.</p>

<p>In conclusion, first solution goes first. If it is impossible to run RVM on Android box and come third solution.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
